<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Perpetual White Belt</title>
    <link>https://www.calmdownkarm.com/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Perpetual White Belt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 09:00:00 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.calmdownkarm.com/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Splat</title>
      <link>https://www.calmdownkarm.com/personal/splat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 09:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.calmdownkarm.com/personal/splat/</guid>
      <description>Picture the idyllic, perfect day. Warm, but not overly so. Sunny, but not enough to be oppressive.
Breathe.
Picture the lush, beautiful green grass slowly rushing towards you as a stranger yells the phrase FLARE FLARE FLARE into your ear. In your mind, some remnant of a Michael Schumacher interview is telling you to relax your body because anything kept braced will break.You should be panicking, but strangely, you&#39;re extremely calm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrations</title>
      <link>https://www.calmdownkarm.com/personal/migrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 09:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.calmdownkarm.com/personal/migrations/</guid>
      <description>For the second time in two years now, I&#39;ve decamped and moved cities. Unexpectedly, there&#39;s a fair amount of culture shock. In the past year I&#39;ve gotten accustomed to being in a very quiet city and Delhi is certainly not that. Plus I&#39;ve had relatives over, other relatives passing away and social obligations that I can&#39;t postpone, so things have been fairly busy; a far cry from how introverted I&#39;d become in Hyderabad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazy Callbacks</title>
      <link>https://www.calmdownkarm.com/personal/lazy-callbacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 09:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.calmdownkarm.com/personal/lazy-callbacks/</guid>
      <description>Around this time last year, I had a few goals in mind for this year. However, I didn&#39;t exactly write them down - and as most of my friends will attest, my memory isn&#39;t the best, so I&#39;m kinda winging it.
  Jiu Jitsu - My biggest goal at the start of the year, was to get all the weird shit with my head sorted out so I could go back to doing jiu jitsu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change</title>
      <link>https://www.calmdownkarm.com/personal/change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 09:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.calmdownkarm.com/personal/change/</guid>
      <description>Four years ago, I sat behind Engineering Hall on campus at the University of Illinois and the enormity of my fuck-up struck for the perhaps the first time. Over the course of a long year and a half I had made a series of bad decisions that ended up in my dropping out of one the best ranked engineering programs in the world, returning to India and starting all over.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>